Guide to the Robert Edward Dawson papers, 1900-2008 RL.00294
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Robert Edward Dawson papers
1880-2008
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Dawson, Robert Edward, 1918-
RL.00294
38.5 Linear Feet
Dr. Robert Edward Dawson (1918-2008) was an African American ophthalmologist and citizen of Durham (Durham County), North Carolina. This collection primarily documents Dawson's professional and civic responsibilities, both local and national. Materials include meeting agendas and packets; reports; memoranda; correspondence, speeches, and writiings. The collection details Dawson's medical practices, teaching, and board memberships at Lincoln Community Health Center, Lincoln Hospital, and Durham County General Hospital/Durham County Hospital Corporation. It also documents his lengthy and high-level involvement with Meharry Medical College and the National Medical Association, as well as a wide array of other organizations and institutions. Personal materials involve Dawson's military service, memorabilia, his documentation for building his house, and his retirement.The collection also contains black and white and color photographs as well as negatives, mostly of family members. Acquired as part of the John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African American History and Culture.
Provenance
The Robert Edward Dawson papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift from 2000 to 2006.
Biographical Note
Dr. Robert Edward Dawson (1918-2008) was an African American ophthalmologist and citizen of Durham (Durham County), North Carolina. He graduated from Clark College with honors in 1939 and from Meharry Medical College with honors in 1943. He spent three years in residency training at Homer G. Philips in St. Louis, Missouri, as a resident in ophthalmology and ear, nose and throat (EENT) surgery. He moved to Durham in 1946 as the first African American EENT surgeon at Lincoln Hospital. Dr. Dawson also served on the attending staff at Watts Hospital and Durham County General Hospital where he served as vice president of staff and later, a member of the board of trustees for the Durham County Hospital Corporation. For many years, Dr. Dawson taught Duke residents in his private office in Durham, at Lincoln Hospital, and in the clinic and operating rooms at Duke Hospital. He was the 79th president of the National Medical Association, and served on many local and national boards and committees. He also served in the United States Air Force (1955-1957), achieving the rank of major.
Collection Overview
This collection primarily documents Dawson's professional and civic responsibilities, both local and national. Materials include meeting agendas and packets; reports; memoranda; correspondence, speeches, and writiings. The collection details Dawson's medical practices, teaching, and board memberships at Lincoln Community Health Center, Lincoln Hospital, and Durham County General Hospital/Durham County Hospital Corporation. It also documents his lengthy and high-level involvement with Meharry Medical College and the National Medical Association, as well as a wide array of other organizations and institutions. Personal materials involve Dawson's military service, memorabilia, his documentation for building his house, and his retirement.The collection also contains black and white and color photographs as well as negatives and one tintype, mostly of family members.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection contains fragile audiovisual/photographic formats that may need to be reformatted before use. Contact Research Services for access.
African American physicians -- North Carolina; African Americans in the professions; African American universities and colleges; Hospitals -- North Carolina; Ophthalmologists; Durham (N.C.); Black-and-white photographs; Color photographs; Negatives (photographs); Tintypes (prints); Dawson, Robert Edward, 1918-; John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African American History and Culture; Meharry Medical College; National Medical Association (U.S.); Lincoln Hospital (Durham, N.C.); Lincoln Community Health Center (Durham, N.C.)
- Hospitals, 1945-1994; undated
  Scope and Contents
  Includes Dawson's records from hospitals where he worked, with the bulk of the material representing Lincoln Hospital. There are departmental and committee records, reports, staff memos, copies of bylaws and constitutions, correspondence, along with outlines of procedures and plans.
  - Duke University Medical Center: Dept. of Ophthalmology, 1968-1980; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Duke University Medical Center: Joint Commission on Allied Health Personnel in Ophthalmology, 1990-1993 (Box 1)
  - Durham County General Hospital, 1976-1988 (Box 1)
  - Durham County General Hospital, 1980-1983 (Box 1)
  - Durham County General Hospital, 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - Durham County General Hospital: Assoc. Health Services Committee, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Durham County General Hospital: Bylaws, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Durham County General Hospital: Bylaws and Constitution Committees, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Durham County General Hospital: Clinical Departments' Rules and Regulations, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Durham County General Hospital: Correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 1)
  - Durham County General Hospital: Department of Laboratory Medicine, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Durham County General Hospital: Disaster Plan, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Durham County General Hospital: Information Manual for Physicians, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Durham County General Hospital: Medical Staff Attending, 1988-1993 (Box 1)
  - Durham County General Hospital: Medical Staff Member, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Durham County General Hospital: Memo, 1981-1986 (Box 1)
  - Durham County General Hospital: Ophthalmology, 1979-1985 (Box 1)
  - Durham County General Hospital: Reports, 1980-1984 (Box 1)
  - Durham County General Hospital: Rules and Regulations, 1976-1978 (Box 1)
  - Durham County General Hospital: Transfer Plan, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Lincoln Community Health Center: Continuation Request, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Lincoln Hospital: I, 1945-1967; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Lincoln Hospital: II, 1953-1974; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Lincoln Hospital: Administrative Director, 1967-1974; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Lincoln Hospital: Anesthesia, Department of, 1968-1973 (Box 2)
  - Lincoln Hospital: Articles on Hospitals, 1968-1974 (Box 2)
  - Lincoln Hospital: Daniels Project, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Lincoln Hospital: Disaster Plan, 1959 (Box 2)
  - Lincoln Hospital: Executive Committee, 1964-1975 (Box 2)
  - Lincoln Hospital: Guide to Laboratory Procedures, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Lincoln Hospital: Health and Hospital Committee, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Lincoln Hospital: Letters, Accounts, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Lincoln Hospital: Letters, Memos, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - Lincoln Hospital: Medical Director, 1968-1969 (Box 2)
  - Lincoln Hospital: Medical Staff, 1973-1975 (Box 2)
  - Lincoln Hospital: Medicine, Department of, 1968-1970 (Box 2)
  - Lincoln Hospital: Nursing Service, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - Lincoln Hospital: OB-GYN, Department of, 1968-1970 (Box 2)
  - Lincoln Hospital: Organization, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Lincoln Hospital: Pediatrics, Department of, 1968-1969 (Box 2)
  - Lincoln Hospital: Physician Assistants, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Lincoln Hospital: Private Diagnostic Clinic, 1968-1972 (Box 2)
  - Lincoln Hospital: Rate for Cost, undated (Box 25)
  - Lincoln Hospital: Room Rates, Fees, 1966-1968 (Box 2)
  - Lincoln Hospital: Surgery, Department of, 1968-1969 (Box 2)
  - Lincoln Hospital: Tissue Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - Lincoln Hospital: Training Program, 1967-1969 (Box 2)
  - Lincoln Hospital: Utilization Committee, 1965-1975 (Box 2)
  - Watts Hospital, 1973-1976; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Watts Hospital: Bylaws of the Staff, 1974 (Box 2)
- Organizations and Institutions, 1940-1999; undated
  Conditions Governing Access
  Collection contains fragile audiovisual/photographic formats that may need to be reformatted before use. Contact Research Services for access.
  Dawson's files from medical and community organizations and institutions where he volunteered his time, or served as a member. The largest amount of material relates to Meharry Medical College and the National Medical Association. Includes agenda and meeting packets, reports, and correspondence related to his service on a wide array of national and local committees and boards.
  - Alpha Omega Alpha Honor Medical Society, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
  - Alpha Phi Alpha, 1980-1996 (Box 3)
  - American Academy of Ophthalmology, 1982-1997 (Box 3)
  - American Board of Ophthalmology, 1979 (Box 3)
  - American Cancer Society, 1953-1963 (Box 3)
  - American Cancer Society, North Carolina Division, 1966-1970 (Box 3)
  - American Hospital Association: 3rd Annual AHA Medical Staff Leadership Forum, 1986; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - American Medical Association: Award, 1980 (Box 3)
  - American Medical Association: House of Delegates Handbook, 1980 (Box 3)
  - American Medical Association: Leadership Guidelines, 1980 (Box 3)
  - American Medical Association: Plan, 1980 (Box 3)
  - American Medical Association: Report on Education and Utilization of Allied Health Manpower, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Association of Governing Boards, 1973-1975 (Box 3)
  - Association of Governing Boards: Task Force, 1975 (Box 3)
  - Better Health Foundation, 1961-1967 (Box 3)
  - Chi Delta Mu Fraternity, 1963-1994 (Box 3)
  - Clark College, 1974-1977 (Box 3)
  - Clark College, 1976-1994; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Clark College: Alumni, 1951-1975 (Box 3)
  - Clark College: Board of Visitors, 1974-1975 (Box 3)
  - Clark College: Citation, 1984 (Box 25)
  - Congressional Black Caucus Health Brain Trust Committee, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Durham Academy of Medicine, Dentistry & Pharmacy, 1990-1994 (Box 3)
  - Durham Business and Professional Chain Rites of Passage (S.A.G.E. Project) for African American Males, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Durham Chamber of Commerce, 1964-1976 (Box 3)
  - Durham Chamber of Commerce: Community Development Committee, 1975 (Box 3)
  - Durham Community House, 1967-1968 (Box 3)
  - Durham County Hospital Corporation, 1976-1984 (Box 4)
  - Durham County Hospital Corporation: Affirmative Action Plan, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Durham County Hospital Corporation: Associated Health Services, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Durham County Hospital Corporation: Board of Trustees, 1975-1980 (Box 4)
  - Durham County Hospital Corporation: Board of Trustees, 1979; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Durham County Hospital Corporation: Board of Trustees, 1979-1980 (Box 4)
  - Durham County Hospital Corporation: Board of Trustees, 1979-1986; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Durham County Hospital Corporation: Board of Trustees, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Durham County Hospital Corporation: Board of Trustees, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Durham County Hospital Corporation: Budget, 1982-1987 (Box 4)
  - Durham County Hospital Corporation: Committee on Eye Care and Eye Bank, 1982-1986 (Box 4)
  - Durham County Hospital Corporation: Development Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - Durham County Hospital Corporation: Joint Conference and Accreditation Committee, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Durham County Hospital Corporation: Personnel Committee, 1975-1985; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Durham County Hospital Corporation: Personnel Committee, 1976-1980 (Box 4)
  - Durham County Hospital Corporation: Personnel Committee, 1981-1997 (Box 4)
  - Durham County Hospital Corporation: Personnel Meeting, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Durham County Hospital Corporation: Reach Out Proposal, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Durham Orange County Medical Society, 1969-1982 (Box 4)
  - Durham Orange County Medical Society: Grievance Committee, 1973 (Box 4)
  - EDSF Standing Committee of Physician Consultants, 1978-1980 (Box 5)
  - Foundation for Better Health of Durham, 1976-1977 (Box 5)
  - Freemasons 33rd Degree Class Program, 1994 (Box 5)
  - FSU, 1989 (Box 5)
  - Greensboro College, 1990-1997 (Box 5)
  - Greensboro College: Board of Visitors, 1980-1984 (Box 5)
  - Greensboro College: Board of Visitors, 1981-1996 (Box 5)
  - Guardsmen, 1962-1982 (Box 5)
  - Guardsmen, 1988-1994; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Lincoln Community Health Center: Board of Directors, 1972-1973; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Lincoln Community Health Center: Financial Plan, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Lincoln Community Health Center: Executive Committee Meeting Agenda, 1972 (Box 25)
  - Masons, 1995 (Box 5)
  - Medical Care Advisory Committee DMA {Division of Medical Assistance], 1980-1993; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Meharry Medical College: Alumni, 1940-1987 (Box 5)
  - Meharry Medical College: Alumni, 1956-1970 (Box 5)
  - Meharry Medical College: Alumni Association, 1976-1993 (Box 5)
  - Meharry Medical College: Alumni Association, 1976-1999 (Box 5)
  - Meharry Medical College: Alumni President, 1969 (Box 5)
  - Meharry Medical College: Alumni President, 1970-1971; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Meharry Medical College: Board of Management, 1966-1974; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Meharry Medical College: Board of Management, 1967-1968 (Box 6)
  - Meharry Medical College: Board of Management letters, 1966-1974 (Box 6)
  - Meharry Medical College: Board of Trustees, 1969-1977 (Box 6)
  - Meharry Medical College: Board of Trustees, 1971-1980; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Meharry Medical College: Board of Trustees, 1974 (Box 6)
  - Meharry Medical College: Board of Trustees, 1974-1977 (Box 6)
  - Meharry Medical College: Board of Trustees, 1975; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Meharry Medical College: Board of Trustees, 1975-1981; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Meharry Medical College: Board of Trustees, 1976; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Meharry Medical College: Board of Trustees, 1977 (Box 7)
  - Meharry Medical College: Board of Trustees, 1978 (Box 7)
  - Meharry Medical College: Board of Trustees, 1979 (Box 7)
  - Meharry Medical College: Board of Trustees, 1979-1983; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Meharry Medical College: Board of Trustees, 1981-1985 (Box 7)
  - Meharry Medical College: Board of Trustees, 1983-1984 (Box 7)
  - Meharry Medical College: Board of Trustees, 1988-1989 (Box 7)
  - Meharry Medical College: Board of Trustees, 1994-1995 (Box 7)
  - Meharry Medical College: Bulletins, 1961-1969; 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Meharry Medical College: Class Reunion, 1956-1973; 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Meharry Medical College: Executive Committee, 1975-1981; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Meharry Medical College: Fund-raising Campaign, 1968-1971 (Box 7)
  - Meharry Medical College: George W. Hubbard Hospital:, 1971-1981; dawsonrobertedward (Box 8)
  - Meharry Medical College: George W. Hubbard Hospital, 1982-1983 (Box 25)
  - Meharry Medical College: George W. Hubbard Hospital: Accreditation, 1975 (Box 8)
  - Meharry Medical College: George W. Hubbard Hospital: Bylaws, 1981 (Box 8)
  - Meharry Medical College: George W. Hubbard Hospital: Financial Reports, 1980 (Box 8)
  - Meharry Medical College: George W. Hubbard Hospital: Hospital Corporation of America Report, 1978 (Box 8)
  - Meharry Medical College: George W. Hubbard Hospital: Preliminary Report, 1981-1982 (Box 8)
  - Meharry Medical College: Hospital & Health Committee, 1971-1982; 4 folders (Box 8)
  - Meharry Medical College: Hubbard Hospital Survey, 1978 (Box 8)
  - Meharry Medical College: Leadership Awards, 1981 (Box 8)
  - Meharry Medical College: Letters, 1954-1970 (Box 8)
  - Meharry Medical College: Letters, 1981 (Box 8)
  - Meharry Medical College: Maupin Inauguration, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Meharry Medical College: Medical Center, undated (Box 8)
  - Meharry Medical College: Newspaper, 1979-1983 (Box 25)
  - Meharry Medical College: Office of Alumni Affairs, 1968 (Box 8)
  - Meharry Medical College: President, 1986-1997 (Box 8)
  - Meharry Medical College: Publications, 1966-1970 (Box 8)
  - Meharry Medical College: Reports to Board of Trustees, 1979-1988 (Box 8)
  - Meharry Medical College: School of Dentistry, 1972-1975 (Box 8)
  - Meharry Medical College: Search Committee, 1981 (Box 8)
  - Meharry Medical College: Trustees Manual, 1978-1980; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Mutual Savings and Loan: Board of Directors, 1981-1992 (Box 9)
  - Mutual Savings and Loan: Board of Directors, 1988 (Box 9)
  - Mutual Savings and Loan: Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1976 (Box 25)
  - National Advisory Committee on Black Higher Education, 1979 (Box 9)
  - National Medical Association and Meharry Medical College, 1973-1982 (Box 9)
  - National Medical Association, 1954-1970 (Box 9)
  - National Medical Association, 1955-1997 (Box 9)
  - National Medical Association, 1986-1992 (Box 9)
  - National Medical Association: 79th Annual Convention Program, 1974 (Box 9)
  - National Medical Association: 82nd Annual Convention Program, 1977 (Box 9)
  - National Medical Association: 84th Annual Convention Program, 1979 (Box 9)
  - National Medical Association: 85th Annual Convention Program, 1980 (Box 9)
  - National Medical Association: 90th Annual Convention Program, 1985 (Box 9)
  - National Medical Association: 95th Annual Convention Program, 1990 (Box 9)
  - National Medical Association: Activities of the President, 1974-1984 (Box 9)
  - National Medical Association: Addresses, 1973-1976 (Box 9)
  - National Medical Association: Application Forms, 1990 (Box 9)
  - National Medical Association: Audiocassette: Coffe--Chase--Johnson--Earle, 1980 (Box 26, Audio-cassette RL00294-CS-0001)
    NMA Board? Meeting held before the annual convention in Dallas {1980?]. Includes discussion of board resolutions, activity of state and regional associations, membership growth, and general communication.
  - National Medical Association: Auxiliary Handbook, 1981 (Box 9)
  - National Medical Association: Awards Committee, 1971 (Box 9)
  - National Medical Association: Black Congress on Health & Law, 1980 (Box 9)
  - National Medical Association: Blue Ribbon Task Force, 1987-1988; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - National Medical Association: Blue Ribbon Task Force, 1988; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - National Medical Association: Board of Trustees, 1970-1973 (Box 9)
  - National Medical Association: Board of Trustees, 1972 (Box 9)
  - National Medical Association: Board of Trustees, 1973; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - National Medical Association: Board of Trustees, 1973-1976 (Box 25)
  - National Medical Association: Board of Trustees, 1974; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - National Medical Association: Board of Trustees, 1974-1975 (Box 10)
  - National Medical Association: Board of Trustees, 1974-1976; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - National Medical Association: Board of Trustees, 1975-1998; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - National Medical Association: Board of Trustees, 1976 (Box 10)
  - National Medical Association: Board of Trustees, 1980-1981 (Box 10)
  - National Medical Association: Committee on Reorganization of the National Office, 1973 (Box 10)
  - National Medical Association: Constitution Committee, 1965-1974 (Box 10)
  - National Medical Association: Continuing Medical Education, 1980-1986 (Box 10)
  - National Medical Association: Conventions, 1969-1979 (Box 10)
  - National Medical Association: Council of Scientific Assembly, 1970-1975 (Box 10)
  - National Medical Association: Council on Financial Aid to Students, 1978 (Box 10)
  - National Medical Association: Distinguished Service Award, 1987-1997 (Box 10)
  - National Medical Association: House of Delegates, 1975-1982 (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association: House of Delegates Handbook, 1974 (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association: House of Delegates Handbook, 1985 (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association: House of Delegates Handbook, 1987; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association: Insurance Committee, 1972-1975; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association: Insurance Program, 1974-1976 (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association: Interviews, 1987 (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association: John Joyner, 1981 (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association: Letters, 1979-1985 (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association: Management Committee, 1974-1976 (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association: Ophthalmology Section, 1976 (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association: Past President's Council, 1983-1995; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association: Planning and Development, 1977-1981 (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association: Project 75, 1972-1974 (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association: Project 75 binder, 1972-1973 (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association: Project Sleep, 1982 (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association: Publications Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association: Region III Convention, 1988 (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association: Region IV Convention Program, 1980 (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association: Retirement Plan Trust, 1975 (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association: SASHEP [Study of Accreditation of Selected Health Educational Programs] Commission Report, 1972 (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association: Search Committee Executive Director, 1974 (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association: Special Task Force, 1981-1983 (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association: Special Task Force Report, 1981-1982 (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association: Strategic Planning, 1987-1988 (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association: Structure- Dawson Speaker of House, 1973-1981 (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association: Survey of Opinion, 1988 (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association: Symposium on Glaucoma, 1966-1973 (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association: Symposium on Strabismus, 1974 (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association: Task Force, 1987 (Box 12)
  - National Medical Association: Time & Place Committee, 1974 (Box 12)
  - National Medical Association: Writings, 1979-1990 (Box 12)
  - National Society for the Prevention of Blindness, 1971-1974 (Box 12)
  - National Society for the Prevention of Blindness: Board of Directors, 1977-1979 (Box 12)
  - National Society to Prevent Blindness, 1978-1979; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - National Society to Prevent Blindness, 1978-1980 (Box 12)
  - National Society to Prevent Blindness, 1978-1981 (Box 12)
  - National Society to Prevent Blindness, 1980-1985 (Box 12)
  - National Society to Prevent Blindness: 75th Anniversary, 1983-1984; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - National Society to Prevent Blindness: Annual Meeting, 1985; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - National Society to Prevent Blindness: Binder, 1978; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - National Society to Prevent Blindness: Board of Directors, 1976-1977 (Box 12)
  - National Society to Prevent Blindness: Board of Directors, 1981-1983 (Box 12)
  - National Society to Prevent Blindness: Board of Directors, 1985 (Box 12)
  - National Society to Prevent Blindness: Board of Directors, 1986-1987 (Box 12)
  - National Society to Prevent Blindness: Medical Advisory Committee, 1977-1984 (Box 12)
  - National Society to Prevent Blindness: Medical Advisory Report to Academy of Ophthalmology, 1979 (Box 12)
  - National Society to Prevent Blindness: Nominating Committee, 1985; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - National Society to Prevent Blindness: Planned Giving Manual, 1982 (Box 13)
  - NC Manpower Development, 1990 (Box 13)
  - [NC State] Commission for the Blind:, 1964-1973 (Box 13)
  - [NC State] Commission for the Blind: Correspondence, 1946-1971 (Box 13)
  - North Carolina Academy of Physician Assistants, 1992 (Box 13)
  - North Carolina Central University, 1980-1994 (Box 13)
  - North Carolina Central University: Board of Trustees, 1973-1979 (Box 13)
  - North Carolina Central University: Board of Trustees, 1974-1996 (Box 13)
  - North Carolina Central University: Board of Trustees, 1974; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - North Carolina Central University: Financial Report, 1972 (Box 13)
  - North Carolina Central University: Handbook and Directory, 1971 (Box 13)
  - North Carolina Central University: Nursing, 1969-1982 (Box 13)
  - North Carolina Central University: Reports, 1971-1979 (Box 13)
  - North Carolina Institute of Medicine, 1993 (Box 13)